[♪ opening theme song playing]
-[footsteps]
-[HAGURE] Akio's a traitor?
Yup.
[yawns] He tried to kill Asa
but failed big time.
I'm betting
someone on the outside
convinced him
to move against us.
We had planned
to grill him and kill him
once the boss man returned.
Then everything blew up
in our faces.
Seriously, Dad, you think
killing solves everything?
Akio was a major part
of our lives.
Surely we can handle this
without murdering him.
[Gabby sighs]
[inhales]
You say that,
but you don't know
the full story.
-[FUYUKI] Kawai, the gardener.
-[gasps]
And those are his daemons
on the floor.
They're strays now.
[Hagure inhales sharply]
Is there anyone here willing
to form a contract with them?
[ALL] Hm...
Um...
I'd like to volunteer, please.
His daemons were
fairly close to my Heave-Ho.
-I think they'd be compatible...
-[TSUGAI] One, two.
...with each other.
-[TSUGAI 1] Three, four.
-[TSUGAI 2] One, two.
-[whining]
-One, two.
-[TSUGAI 1] Three, four.
-[TSUGAI 2] One, two.
-One, two.
-[FUYUKI] Excuse me.
This pair is called
Gokko-Itachi.
No individual names
at the moment.
Their previous master
was Sanosuke Kawai.
-He was murdered.
-[squealing]
Akio Kuroya killed him
while trying to escape.
Still think he should live?
Why would he want
to kill someone
who is like family to all of us?
Damn it.
If we were to report this death
to the police,
they'd want to investigate
the manor.
We'll have to say
he abandoned his job instead.
I'm the one who brought Kawai
into the fold.
He had no relatives to speak of.
-He'll be easy to erase.
-[gasps]
[HAGURE] Jin, no!
[breathes shakily]
You can't do this to him.
He put in years
of service for us.
At the very least,
he deserves a proper funeral.
What you're proposing
is just heartless. Please, Dad.
Don't do this!
After all, it was
your strict ways
that caused Akio
to close himself off to us.
You treat people like family,
but you don't think twice
about cutting them out
for the smallest offenses.
You kill people
for making a single mistake.
If you weren't so stubborn
and opened up your heart,
maybe he would've told us
why he thought
he had to betray the clan.
What he saw that we didn't.
And if he'd done that,
maybe he wouldn't have been
so callous.
Maybe Kawai
would still be alive!
Hagure!
[gasps]
[GABBY] Sensei...
Do you know why
I like your stories?
There are no bad people in them.
This world sucks big time.
So reading your manga
makes me feel,
I don't know... safe.
The people you create
would never try to hurt me
or want to get rid of me.
A happy fantasy world
sounds pretty nice right now,
because our reality is full
of unbelievably shitty people
doing awful things
to one another.
Myself included.
Still, I'll do everything
in my power
to protect the Kagemori clan
because it's where I belong.
I want you to keep
drawing your cute little stories
in a place you feel safe.
And I want Asa to live a normal,
peaceful life.
Akio chose the parents
who abandoned him
over the people who gave him
a home.
He betrayed those
who cared about him.
I don't know how important
his blood family was to him,
but I won't forgive
anyone who tries
to destroy this clan.
I would kill my own parents
if they tried to do that,
with no hesitation.
You can be lenient with assholes
and hope they'll change,
but that rarely ever happens,
which is why
your only good option
is to take them out
before it's too late.
That's the real world.
Please forgive me.
[gasps] Asa?
Gabby, do not let her go off
alone by herself!
Yeah, I know.
Damn it, Asa! Wait!
[BUNBUN] Hey, Haruo?
Why is it that human beings
turn on their friends?
No daemon would ever
betray their partner.
[Haruo sighs]
[GABBY] Get back here.
You can't run off by yourself.
Akio could
still be hiding out here.
Asa!
[ASA] Kawai is dead.
And for what?
I'm the one Akio wanted to kill.
Kawai wasn't his enemy,
or even a fighter.
If his hands were dirty,
it was with soil,
not with someone's blood.
He was a normal man
who didn't wish death on anyone.
He was just trying
to live his life!
It's my fault.
[grunts] Idiot!
No, it isn't!
The people to blame are the ones
who want to exploit
all your power.
What happened isn't your fault,
damn it.
Didn't Yuru tell you to stop
saying sorry for everything?
Apologize for dumb shit again
and I'll kick your ass.
More than I already have.
[Asa whimpers, cries]
[ASA] I'm sorry, Gabby.
[Gabby grunts]
What did I just say?
♪
[scraping]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[breathing uneasily]
[sighs]
Father's... not here.
I'm on my own.
I need to clean
this mess up all by myself.
I have to.
[grunting]
This bandit tried to kill me.
So I can't hesitate to act!
[grunts]
[panting]
Do what needs to be done.
Don't waver.
No one's coming to help.
Nobody's going
to fix anything for me.
This is the only way.
Out here...
I'm alone.
[Yuru breathes softly]
Uh?
Hold on. Where am I?
Oh, right.
I fell asleep
in the futon closet.
[gasps]
[LEFT] Ah, are you faring well,
Yuru?
Huh?
You scared
the crap out of me, Left!
[Right chuckles]
So, what are you doing
down there?
[LEFT] Guarding you.
-My mobility is still limited...
-Yup!
...but I can keep
a watchful eye on you
from this spot on the floor.
[YURU] Wonderful. Thanks.
Uh? Hey, you're awake.
Are you feeling any better?
Yeah, I'm not as sluggish.
Do you know what time it is?
[KEN] A little past noon.
Huh?
Good morning.
Or afternoon, I guess.
You're not near as pale
as you were.
I was scared. Are you all right?
-How is your shoulder?
-And fever.
You must be on the mend.
-I'm so glad.
-[neighs]
[Yuru sighs]
[YURU] Hm?
[Yuru screams]
What was that for?
So, did you sleep okay?
[groans] I had some
less than pleasant dreams.
[HANA] Oh, dang.
Well, have some food
and try to forget them.
Good idea.
I'll whip us up a late lunch.
-[Right chuckles]
-We can eat together.
Sound good?
[footsteps]
[GABBY] Took you
long enough, Jinny.
Could you clean this up?
Were they
Higashi Village agents?
Gotta be. Just look.
They managed to kill Asa.
[Jin breathes uneasily]
[GABBY] Our girl died
and gained the power of Break.
[ASA] Jin...
I'm sorry. [cries]
I'm sorry you have
to clean this up.
It's my fault.
I'm sorry.
I'm... sorry.
I'm sorry. Huh?
Think nothing of it.
Cleaning up messes
is my job, after all.
There's nothing
that you need to apologize for.
I'll handle this.
You get some rest
and let your mind at ease.
[Asa gasps]
[snoring]
-[ASA] Gabs, you're heavy.
-[groaning]
[GABBY] How did you sleep?
Not great.
I had some bad dreams.
That's lame.
Grab something to eat
and forget about them.
Wonder if there's
anything tasty in the kitchen.
[birds chirping]
Good morning.
Or afternoon, rather.
What are you doing here?
Please tell me you haven't
been keeping watch.
I worried someone would strike
thinking our guard was down.
As if we wouldn't expect
another attack.
But I didn't hear a peep
the whole night.
[ASA] The whole night?
[NATSUKI] Mm.
I'm gonna go take a shower.
Watch her for me,
will you, Gabby?
Duh-doy!
Hey, Natsuki, wait.
[ALL] Hm?
I'm sorry--
[Gabby grunting]
Thanks for being
so on top of it.
[Natsuki chuckles]
I'll come back
when I'm done showering.
And then we'll begin
math lessons as usual.
What?
Can't she get a single day
to rest up?
[BABAMARU] Staying up all night
is bad for your skin, Natsuki.
[JIJIMARU]
You should nap, Natsuki.
[GABBY] Yeah, you heard 'em.
Go straight to bed.
[Natsuki sighs] Hm.
Fine.
I'll settle in for some R and R
once you've finished
today's problems.
Hurry up and solve
all the equations
so I can go relax.
[ASA AND GABBY] Monster.
[exclaims] Hold on a sec.
Can I use Break on math?
Don't use a legendary daemon
on stupid BS like that!
[NATSUKI] Hm?
-[footsteps]
-[FUYUKI] Natsuki.
Thirsty? Jin said
we should take the day off.
[Natsuki groans]
Haruo, care for a glass?
Join us.
We'll drink, then sleep.
We can think about Akio
after we've sobered up.
Booze and an all-nighter?
That's hell on your skin, dummy.
[Natsuki chuckles]
On second thought, let's put you
to sleep right away.
Play nice.
[Yuru groans]
All right!
What is he doing?
Learning stuff.
I got him
an electronic dictionary
to look up words
he doesn't know.
[YURU] Since I came down
the mountain,
I've come across a lot of words
I can read but don't understand.
Now I don't have to ask people
to explain them to me.
Oh, interesting. So you're using
hiragana mode, huh?
[YURU] Yeah.
By the way,
what did you study
back when you were still
in the village?
[YURU] I read
whatever texts Dera brought
from the outside world.
Sun Tzu and the like.
Yuru, you're amazing!
A smart barbarian!
[YURU] I only said I read it,
not that I understood it.
Oh, what?
Is this magic?
[YURU] I honestly have no idea.
But it is useful.
-Here.
-Thanks so much.
Azami, I'm sure you're confused
after being brought down here
so suddenly.
Are you afraid?
Well, I don't know
what's going on,
but I've gotten used to that,
so it's not scary really.
Honestly, being super confused
all the time feels normal.
I know just what you mean!
[AZAMI] Also,
the rice here is good.
[YURU] I know, right?
-[AZAMI] And the cold box...
-This is nice.
Azami seems to be
in good spirits.
-[AZAMI] Yeah.
-[YURU] Ah, yes, in the kitchen.
Although, I bet she wants
to go back to the village.
[Yuru and Azami chatter]
Where Ma is.
I hope she's okay.
[Right grunts]
Cease your moping.
If you walk around
looking gloomy,
you'll scare away your blessing.
[BOTH] Left and Right!
Oh, hey! Did you both
reattach your limbs?
[RIGHT] Yes.
We are whole once more!
But we've yet to fully recover.
That said, the stone adhesive
Dera bought did work well.
[RIGHT] We could get
chopped to bits,
and it'd be no problem. [laughs]
Maybe try not
to get anything cut off again.
Uh? Hold up.
Where's Dera?
I thought he was here.
[crowd cheering]
Yeah!
[groaning]
Mm?
[groans] Mm?
-[DERA] Hey, buddy. Lose big?
-[HAMURA] You, too?
I was hoping for a windfall.
Gotta support the kiddos,
you know?
Yeah.
I'm out here 'cause I'm hoping
to pay off an old debt.
I even took out a loan
so I'd be able to place
some bigger bets.
But the next race will be ours.
You've gotta do right
by those kiddos of yours.
Hell yes!
[ASA, GABBY AND HANA] Scumbags.
[HAMURA] First things first,
time to borrow some more money.
[phone chimes]
Oh, man.
Just great.
[DERA] We've been called
to a meeting
of Higashi Village agents.
[HANA] They want everyone
with an official position
to be there.
Naturally, the message came
from a bandit.
What? Them again?
They are definitely planning
to put you through the wringer
for the Fujimurayama warehouse
crapfest.
And they are gonna demand
that you hand over Yuru.
Yeah, no doubt.
Do you want me to go with you
and teach them all a lesson?
-I must object.
-Eh?
For real, Yuru, listen to Left.
That's a bad idea.
Since we're not
in top shape yet,
we'll have to
sit this fight out.
It wouldn't be wise to hunt down
these knaves by yourself.
Fair point.
Then once you're both
fully recovered,
we'll go teach 'em
a lesson together!
[KEN] Don't make it sound
like a party.
A lot of
the Higashi Village agents
who'll be at the meeting
are also Daemon Wielders.
You know what that means.
I'll be skipping.
What? That's totally unfair.
Now if I blow off the meeting,
they'll be suspicious
as heck, you bum!
What's up, guys?
How's it hanging?
Ah, Gravedigger.
It's good to see you,
Hana babe.
You're still alive?
[BANDIT] You hear much
from Tadera these days?
Nope, not a word.
-Why, hasn't he shown up yet?
-No.
He hasn't responded to
any of my messages either.
Well, that's weird.
If he's gone dark, it could mean
he's hiding something.
[BANDIT] When I ran into him
at the Fujimurayama warehouse,
he told me he had no intention
of giving us Yuru
or cooperating with the village.
He betrayed Higashi Village?
I bet that good-for-nothing rat
is plotting to use the Seal kid
for his own selfish gain.
He sucks so bad.
When we find that steaming turd,
we'll show him what's what.
[BANDIT] Jeez.
She really hates him.
-[vehicle approaching]
-[BOTH] Hm?
[MALE OFFICIAL]
Ah, the president's here.
♪
Right, then.
Is everybody present?
We're missing Tadera.
[PRESIDENT] Hmm, that figures.
[SHIZUKU] Good evening.
[KAGARI]
Lovely to see you again.
[Jiro whines]
[DERA] Ooh!
It's a message from Jiro.
[YURU] President?
The man in charge of
the village's minions down here.
He's the one who assigns jobs
to everybody.
I'd rather not fight
with the guy.
But he also wants
to control Break and Seal,
giving the village
power to rule the world, so...
From what I can gather,
Gravedigger,
Ryu Tadera has taken Yuru
and disappeared into hiding.
Is that true?
Yeah, apparently so.
And you haven't been
in contact with them lately?
It's like I told
the bandits, sir.
All I did was bring those
guys down the mountain
and drop them off
somewhere close to Dera's place.
-Haven't heard a peep since.
-[sniffs]
So why didn't you tell us
you took the boy
away from the village?
Don't you think maybe
that's the kind of information
you should have
relayed to us immediately?
In fact, if we hadn't talked
to the shaman already,
we wouldn't have known
about Yuru
or the fact that the village
was being torn apart
by enemy forces.
Hey, buddy,
find someone else to blame.
It's not like Dera's been
sharing intel with me either.
[PRESIDENT] Shall we recap?
In the wake
of the horrible attacks,
Higashi Village is in shambles.
Yuru is off the mountain,
Asa has Break and is under
the influence of the Kagemoris,
and the bandits
took heavy losses.
With Tadera and the Shaman gone,
few people know how to get
through the village barrier.
I think you'll all agree
we've found ourselves
in a dire situation
for which I offer a solution.
We can't keep waiting for orders
-from Granny Yamaha.
-[Jiro sniffs]
It would slow us down
and make failure more likely.
[president groans]
From now on, I think it's best
that I take over command
of our operations down here.
[YURU] "Ulterior motives"?
Huh? What?
The old man's after Hana?
Good luck, creep.
She'll kill you!
Oh, hmm.
He meant that kind
of ulterior motive. Much better.
[PRESIDENT] Our first order
of business is to find Tadera
and figure out
where he's stashed Yuru.
[FEMALE OFFICIAL]
What if he resists?
We can take him down
without a fight easy.
He doesn't have daemons,
so we'll just throw ours at him.
-[Jiro grunts]
-Jiro?
-[HANA] What did you find?
Come here, take a look.
Seems harmless enough.
They're daemon relics, right?
[SHIZUKU] Correct.
[KAGARI] They're active daemons.
We sense souls within them.
Okay, so who do they
belong to, then?
And why are they
in this warehouse?
No clue.
Someone could form a contract
with them.
[all gasp]
♪
[Jiro barks]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[GONZO]
A daemon who infects relics
and causes them to explode.
We need more intel.
Know anything?
I have no information
on anyone with such abilities.
Then we're dealing with a power
that's unknown to us.
Let's make sure everybody
in the manor
checks their daemons at once.
They could be infected.
Bunbun had an idea.
It's possibly a daemon
from the West.
The West. Hm...
Perhaps...
No, it couldn't be.
Nishino Village was destroyed.
A drowned corpse
at the bottom of a reservoir.